Hello everyone, welcome back to another edition of this just in I'm joined here with Leonardo Guerrero
hello, and also here back under
extreme circumstances and with a little bit of
hesitation hesitation I would say
Katherine Mathis
She didn't do very well in her game show last time, but you didn't do very well
Is it Mathis or math? Mathis
How do you spell that?
Like Johnny Mathis so M-A-T-H, but E-S, not I
Who is Johnny Mathis?
Well, Johnny Mathis was an I, so it's exactly the same as him for the vowel
He's a singer
God Leo, don't you know anything?
From back in the day
Who the hell is Johnny Mathis?
We could pee in him
Only Katherine knows about him
Ooh, well
Well, look who knows more now
If we were to have a game show, I would win
With your made-up singers
Anyway
Do you know Johnny Guerrero?
He was a singer too
Yeah, Johnny Guerrero
Alright, and also back in LA
Also is Claudia
The new intern for the Praxis Pod family
But do we really have to introduce interns?
Of course
What are you racist now?
What are you racist?
I'm a Gerarchic racist
He's a Gerarchicist
We just made up the word EnglishPod.com
Alright, so we're gonna be introducing
the lessons for this week
and also we're gonna be talking about
the country of the week
Is it Mexico now?
I'm guessing it's an English speaking country
No, it's the country that has a lot of users
or has a lot of activity from
Russia
Actually Russia was last week
That was last week
No, that's a good guess
but maybe not
Maybe, maybe not
I won't say until the end
But we're gonna be looking at the lesson
for Monday and it's actually really cool
because it's the third part of the
whole English decade series
so we're gonna be looking at English
from the 1970s
Oh, far out man
Funky, yeah
So we're gonna have cool music on it
and we're gonna have a lot of
born in this decade but we still use them today
For example
For example, this word, mellow out
Uh oh
There's some connotations with that word
Like what? Nothing
Come on, you know
A big part of the culture of the 70s
is drug culture
So while obviously we do not promote that
I can say it, it's an American
cultural fact that a lot of people
were experimenting with drugs
and they obviously are illegal
but it became also a part of popular culture
so these like drug words
and kind of mellowing out
and doing these kind of activities
is very wrapped up in 70s
So I could say mellow out
actually means to let go and relax and chill
but you can also say let's go mellow out
and let's go do some drugs
Yeah, relaxation
Actually Catherine knows a lot about this
because she was on that ceremony show
Oh, I haven't heard this in a while
Go ahead
It looks a lot like Donna
Except that she's not a red head
I'm not a red head and I don't look
like Donna
But that's like minor details
Here's the thing, maybe you think
it's because of my voice
It could be the voice
It's the attitude, the voice
You're tall
You actually do look like a brunette version
Donna can beat me down
You could beat me down
We are both sarcastic
We'll have to do a lesson where I'm Donna
Alright, so 1970s
and on Wednesday we're going to be
treating a very serious topic
We're going to be talking about global warming
I'm not a fan, that's why
I'm sweating right now
You're sweating because of global warming
It shouldn't be this hot right now
Just turn on the air conditioner
That's going to fix our problem
It'll just pull things right down
So what do you guys think about
global warming, is it a real issue
a real problem or are we just like making things up
Oh yeah, oh yeah, we're going down
We're going down
It's going to be Waterworld in like
2060 and then who's going to be laughing?
Kevin Cocter
He got so much crap for that movie
but you know
He's prepared
Maybe he was just a very Prussian dude
I really like that movie actually
I like that movie too, I think it was awesome
There's a lot of people who
doesn't like it at all
Why don't you like this movie?
It's so hokey
It's like Pirates in the future
It's awesome
And it's kind of like
Have you seen the Universal Studios show?
Yeah, the Universal Studios show was awesome
And he had gills behind his ears
So he could swim away
No, he could breathe under the water
Yeah, exactly
So global warming, this is an advanced lesson
So for all of those listeners who want to
be challenged a little bit
and it actually has a lot of useful phrases
and a lot of vocabulary that you can use to
argue your points of view or to
maybe disagree with someone
And on Friday
we have a great lesson
This is why we have these girls here
along with us today because it's called
Baby I'm Sorry
Is it part of
the series you've been doing?
No, this is not I'm Sorry I Love You
This actually has to do with
this whole usage
You're telling somebody that you love them
saying the words I love you
Jeez
So when you're saying baby I'm sorry to me?
Baby I'm sorry but I love you?
No
I hope that's not the way it happens
when you first said to me
Baby I'm sorry
Baby I'm sorry but I love you?
Well maybe you have to apologize
What's the situation? I'm a little confused
Alright, so basically the girl
she's asking him where this
relationship is going
The typical question, where is this
relationship going? We've been
together, what are we?
Why does it have to come so early?
The definition conversation
that works not very well
So what do you do in these circumstances
or when the lady
tells you I love you, what do you say
to that if you don't love her?
You say I love you too
Or like
yeah me too
Yeah, I also
feel very special
for you
Write that gacha hot stuff
with a wing
Here's looking at you kiddo
What do you say? Or what do you do?
So this is something in a little bit
of a comical sense
this is what happens in her dialogue
and well also the difference of
saying I love you versus
being in love with
There's a big difference, you can be in love
with someone that don't say that to
Like Liliana
is in love with
Astin Kutcher, doesn't mean that
she's ever gonna say I love you Astin
She probably will, I think she has already
Or like you can love someone
you care for them, you love them
but you're not in love with them
you don't have that physical
relationship with them too
And also this question
where is this relationship going?
Yeah, yeah
Why are you so nostalgic, what's going on?
Oh no, it's just
it's usually one of those conversations that like
I don't wanna make a stereotype but like
one party tends
to make more than the other
like what are we, are we in a relationship
we're a couple
a lot of times it's the girl who brings it up
who wants to know like are we together
like are you dating other people
What does it mean, like what are the different stages
when you're together means like
you're a couple, like exclusive
like I'm not seeing other people
So you can be together but
not exclusive, like when you start dating
maybe you're not exclusive, you never had the conversation
so you have a date with like
3 different guys
You don't do that?
What didn't you guys tell me about?
See, this is why English Pod brings solutions
to your everyday needs
So I can be dating somebody but
still be dating other people
Jesus!
I've been doing all this time
So this is why the question pops up
what are we, so it's kind of asking
for exclusivity? Yep, saying like
I wanna commit to not seeing
other people So you should do the same
Alright, so dating, you can date
multiple people
Why not? So how do you call
that stage when you cannot
see multiple people anymore?
We're exclusive But
how do you call that relationship?
Oh, we're exclusive
We're not, yeah
We're exclusive, here's my exclusive
Not really a linguistic difference, you just say like
we've been on a couple dates, or we're dating, like we're together
So I think you would say we're
together, right? You wouldn't say we're dating anymore
It changes, I feel like
I think I'm in that age where my age is the
transition, so I remember
a couple years back it was talking
and then you were going out, you were boyfriend and girlfriend
that's how you'd introduce, but now I don't know
how to do it, like does he ask you out?
Are you just
automatically boyfriend and girlfriend?
I think it has to do like
I don't know, I usually
just say like, well if you've been
on a couple dates and you're regularly
kissing or something
Yeah, when you kiss in public
that's, or hold hands
Or you say like, I'm seeing this guy
Like, I'm seeing someone
Yeah, I think the worst
is holding hands
Holding hands in public
it's pretty
Intense
It's a next step of commitment
Not necessarily in public, but in front of your friends, yes
when you're like, oh hi everyone, this is
blah blah blah
Geez, what about introducing
your boyfriend or girlfriend to your parents?
Oh Lord, that's a huge step
That's a huge step
You don't mind that, my dad's ex-motorist
like a very
intimidating, and he's 6'4
and he's a big guy
He used to threaten to go load the guns
Like, you wait right here while I go get the gun
I mean, he's a nice, he's a kind guy
he's very funny, but like, he's a very intimidating person
Does he have like a big
afro curly hair?
No? Oh no, that's done
Alright, so holding hands
kissing in public maybe, or
presenting your boyfriend or girlfriend to your parents
Big steps
Alright, interesting, very good talk everyone
Interesting getting the
female's perspective of
relationships and commitments
and all this stuff, so,
listeners, let us know what you think, or
how things are done maybe in your country, like
how do you start dating somebody, do you
automatically do it, is it just a
one time thing, or
maybe, because I know that this dating
culture in the United States is very
different from other countries
Yeah, I totally changed from country to country
In America, we don't really work that way
I don't think we call it dating, or if we do
we just, it's called cheating
But that's a different story, maybe
we'll get to that next week
Alright, now it's
time for us to talk about the country of the week
Yeah, so
this week, yes? Clues, I want to win
Give me clues, I love trivia
Yeah, let's do clues
You want to win? Okay, you want to do clues?
This country is in the Americas
Mexico
No, it's not
Mexico, it's Brazil
Really?
You were a cheat
I think you saw my notes
You're a cheat, you knew
Alright, so the country of the week is Brazil
We have a lot of listeners from Brazil
Actually, we've had a
decreasing activity from our Brazilian
listeners, we had a user who used to comment
a lot, his name was Fernando Cortes
but we haven't seen him in a while, but we've seen
Brazilians come on, so we want to
motivate people to come to the website
to comment on the lessons section
and to let us know you're out there, we know that
you are logging on to the website
so come out
Yeah, let's shout out
Shout out to Brazil
and Brazilians, and carnival
Enjoy la playa
Brazilian girls
Brazilian girls, garotas
My roommate's Brazilian
So when are we going out?
I'm cooking dinner, so you want to come over
Is that a date?
With my two girl roommates
Is that a multiple date?
No, no, no
It could be a double date if I come
It is the 21st century, the lines are going out
Alright
I think I have a boyfriend
Maybe, we haven't talked about it
You know, the talk
Really?
So, you're kind of like in this purgatory
that we were talking about before
Yeah, exactly
I think it's time for you to say
Where are we?
What are we?
What would you call this thing
we're doing?
I don't want to bring it up
You gotta do it, it's never going to happen
We could bring it up
Well, I think now that he will just give us his email address
We'll email him this podcast
Absolutely
So if you're out there
Hey, we want to know what you're with Claudia
Come on, stop it
Alright guys, so
also I want to congratulate Russia and Japan
who are our countries of the week
in the last two weeks, they've been coming out
and they've been speaking on the website
Spasibo
So yeah, it's great to see you out there
And well, anything else you want to add before we leave?
Thanks for inviting me back
I might have gotten a little out of control last time
but I feel like I've been
totally with it this time
I think we will have you back on our next show
You behaved pretty well this time
My bad sight comes out when I do this game
Well, we'll leave it to our users
If you want Catherine to come back, vote
on our website
Will Catherine stay or will she leave?
Please vote for me, you know you love me
Alright, so we'll see you guys next week
and until then, it's bye
Bye
EnglishPod.com